Vineeth S

9164488928 | vineethvini8888@gmail.com | Bengaluru, Karnataka, India | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

I have been employed as a Data Scientist; I've played a key role in a project dedicated to crafting a revolutionary no-code Al platform. The primary focus has been on developing digital twins for industrial manufacturing equipment, showcasing my expertise in driving innovation at the intersection of data science and industry advancements.

SKILLS

- Python
- Machine Learning
- Digital Twin
- Scikit-Learn
- Pandas

- NumPv
- Predictive Maintenance
- SQL
- Business Requirement Gathering
- Flutter

EXPERIENCE

System Engineer/Data Scientist, Tata Consultancy Services, Oct 2022 - Current

Location: Bengaluru, India

- Designed and delivered an Asset Twin-based predictive maintenance model to generate real-time equipment "health priority alerts" which reduces asset downtime.
- Spearheading the development of digital twins, I have taken ownership from gathering data from historian till the deployment of model in customer environment.
- Worked with business units and Performed ground truth analysis on historian data.
- Successfully enhanced the efficiency of the Carbonation Tower process by working on its Process Twin, providing
 actionable prescriptions and advisories to operators, resulting in the optimization of final product quality to maximum
 achievable levels.
- Product Overview-TCS InTwin

Assistant System Engineer/Associate Data Scientist, Tata Consultancy Services, Aug 2022 - Oct 2022

Location: Bengaluru, India

- I have designed and developed an Auto Machine Learning (AutoML)algorithm for a revolutionary no-code Al platform capable of dynamically selecting the best model for a given task.
- A significant aspect of my contribution involved crafting an AutoML algorithm that seamlessly navigates through data cleaning, auto feature engineering, auto feature selection and best model selection.
- I actively contributed to the creation and advancement of a self-learning algorithm.
- This innovative algorithm played a pivotal role in generating and maintaining model revisions autonomously, ensured that our models continually evolved and adapted to changing data.

Assistant System Engineer Trainee/Associate Data Scientist, Tata Consultancy Services, Aug 2021 –Sept 2022 Location: Bengaluru, India

- I have developed multiple fundamental algorithms for no-code AI platform. These algorithms, carefully crafted for offline usability.
- These algorithms used to perform generalized operation like data pre-processing, feature engineering and diagnostic analysis.
- Some of the notable algorithm that I have developed are triple exponential smoothening, chi square feature selection, variance inflation factor, garbage data cleaning, corelation based feature selection and extract time period.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

Electronics and communication engineering, BGS institute of technology, Karnataka

Graduated: July 2021

CGPA: 7.9

CERTIFICATION

- Python for Data Science- Issued by NPTEL
- Machine Learning- Issued by Coursera
- Algorithms and Data Structures in Python Issued by Udemy

LANGUAGES

- Kannada, Native or Bilingual Proficiency
- English, Professional Working Proficiency